#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/osama-mustafa-43212923 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Settlements
EOD Processing
Customer Service

# Osama Mustafa

Application Consultant at Euronet Pakistan (Private) Limited Pakistan

# Summary

Experienced System Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the financial services industry. Strong information technology professional skilled in Analytical Skills, Project Implementation, ISO8583, Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS), and Mobile Payments.

# Experience

**Euronet Pakistan** 

6 years 5 months

Application Consultant

April 2021 - Present (1 year)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

Asst. Application Consultant

January 2019 - April 2021 (2 years 4 months)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

System Engineer

January 2018 - January 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Bahria Complex III, M.T Khan RD. Karachi

Credit Card System (ICCS) Validation, Testing, Analysis, Configuration, UI Testing

Provide Technical support for the Client Queries and Problems causing declined

ATM addition

POS

Responsible to daily operations / Incoming & outgoing process of authorization transactions and provide reports to clients.

Preparing monthly MIS reports and Monthly Volumes statistics of Cards transactions, Merchant ID's, Terminals ID's, MNET – Switch MIS, Member Banks, CMS, Monthly Transactions, Merchant setups & Payment etc. with transactions report operations to senior management.

Handling Queries, Complaints & Correspond independently to the utmost satisfaction of customers.

Data extraction from database using SQL for Customers.

Providing Technical Level Support for Alternate Distributed Channels Transactions (ATM & POS).

Root Cause Analysis of the problem for Resolution of issue.

Responsible for deployment of the package both onsite and from in-house (remotely).

Involved in UAT sessions, in order to validate the system requirements and final goals.

Give complete product training to the fresh resources in the team Acquirer / ATMs / POS / Channels configuration into the system.

#### Associate System Engineer

September 2016 - January 2018 (1 year 5 months)

Bahria Complex III, M.T Khan RD. Karachi

#### **OPERATIONS & MONITORING**

ITM 4.3

**CUP** 

**MNET** 

**GATEWAY** 

**VISA** 

**EOD** 

#### Responsibilities

- Provides training / guidelines to newly hired staff customer support analysts.
- · EOD processing for all clients
- Monitor transactions
- Provide first level Customer / Technical support to the customers (Member Banks).
- .Execution of different queries on ITM 4.3 for transaction extraction purpose.
- VISA /MasterCard transaction settlement processing (Outgoing / Incoming Transactions).
- Perform incident management in case of any incident reported by client or customer.
- 24\*7 Technical and Operational Support
- Perform investigation on daily log files to provide initial information and resolution details to customer.
- · Provide daily Reports to the Client.
- CMS (Card linking d-linking)

• Execution of daily and monthly backups and coordination with IBM data centre team for tap library upload.

Asst. Customer Support Analyst November 2015 - September 2016 (11 months) Bahria Complex III, M.T Khan Road, Karachi

### PEARL CONTINENTAL HOTEL, KARACHI C.E COORDINATOR/ SHIFT SUPERVISOR

February 2014 - November 2015 (1 year 10 months)

KARACHI, PAKISTAN

GFK Etilize Private Limited Associate Data Processing Engineer February 2013 - November 2013 (10 months) Karachi, Pakistan

Extract Data from different sources for different products for International Clients

## Education

Karachi University

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science · (2009 - 2012)